<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://seminolecandlecompany.com/blogs/our-products.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://seminolecandlecompany.com/blogs/our-products"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://seminolecandlecompany.com/blogs/our-products.atom"/>
  <title>Seminole Candle Company - Our Products</title>
  <updated>2018-06-25T21:09:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Seminole Candle Company</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://seminolecandlecompany.com/blogs/our-products/soy-what</id>
    <published>2018-06-25T21:09:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T07:19:38-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://seminolecandlecompany.com/blogs/our-products/soy-what"/>
    <title>Soy What?!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Jenny Harrison</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>[</strong><span>CustomerService@SeminoleCandleCompany.com</span><strong>]</strong><span> </span><strong>[</strong><span>803.261.5764</span><strong>]</strong></p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0016/2984/7596/files/original-on-transparent-bg-f441da61-f87a-4fa7-86c7-56567414e090_small.jpg?v=1528985647" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<p>Seminole Candle Company chooses soy wax as the base of your favorite candles for many reasons. First, it's a renewable wax derived from soybeans, unlike other waxes. The <a href="http://candles.org">National Candle Association</a> states that candles are present in 7 out of 10 homes in the U.S. <strong>Can you believe that? </strong>Guess how many pounds of wax that equates to. . . . . . . . . . . ........ more than <strong>1 BILLION</strong> pounds per year! That's more weight than over <strong>1,000 Boeing 747 airplanes!!</strong> </p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0016/2984/7596/files/f95a85d0f3951946f8203a701993a411_compact.jpg?v=1529968806" alt=""> <img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0016/2984/7596/files/f95a85d0f3951946f8203a701993a411_compact.jpg?v=1529968806" alt=""> <img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0016/2984/7596/files/f95a85d0f3951946f8203a701993a411_compact.jpg?v=1529968806" alt=""></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Those staggering figures, as well as working with people and candles in many formats like baby showers, weddings, and event/retail candles, contributes to the second reason we use soy wax. You're breathing in the product I'm making. That's a big deal! Just like cooking, my other love besides candle making, I would never want you to eat or breathe something that wasn't the healthiest or best I know how to make.</p>
<p>Seminole Candles burn efficiently, evenly, and cleanly because of the combination of soy wax and cotton wicking. Keep your wicks trimmed to 1/4", and you won't experience a longer burning or more fragrant offering than our soy wax can provide. We hear it all the time,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"the candles we used to buy tunnel down and are unusable after a few uses", or "they leave black soot on the jar which seems unhealthy."<em>  </em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Those statements lead to the third reason of many, many more, because that's just not right! Buying expensive candles and not being able to enjoy them because they don't burn correctly, is bad enough. The fact that they're typically made from paraffin wax is even worse, as paraffin is a petroleum byproduct. Remember the whole candles are burned in 7 out of 10 homes using over 1 billion pounds of wax thing!</p>
<p>Choosing soy is clearly a safer, environmentally friendly alternative. It made me wonder why it wasn't offered by large candle companies.  It's because it's not easy to work with compared to other waxes. It's an agricultural product, so batches can vary from crop to crop, not adhering to national brand standards and shipping demands. Soy wax also has a lower melt-point than paraffin and other waxes, making it unappealing to national suppliers.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
